# Baofang (Luna) Zhang

Green Card holder

Address: Cary NC E-mail: zhangbf159@gmail.com Phone: (330) 319-3863 LinkedIn: in/Baofang Zhang

#### **SUMMARY**

Over five years working experience in data processing, analyzing, machine learning; experienced in supervised learning as well as unsupervised learning in data science; excellent communication skills with both technical and non-technical; self-starter and team player with cross-functional teams at all levels.

## **SKILLS**

- Python (Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, SciPy), SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL), Jupyter, Tableau, Spark, Google Cloud, Linux, Jiar, Git, MS Project, Excel, Slack, SharePoint
- Machine Learning (Regression, Classification, Clustering), Optimization, Data Mining, Statistical /
  Predictive Modeling, Data Visualization, Logistic Regression, Decision Trees, Random Forest, GBoost,
  XGBoost, SVM, K-nearest Neighbor (KNN), Naïve Bayes, Feature Engineering, NLP (NLTK), Deep
  Learning (Tensorflow, Keras), Experiment Design & Analysis, A/B test experiment

### WORKING EXPERIENCES

Data ScientistSan Mateo, CATechlent,Inc02/2020- 08/2020

- Built a price optimization model as a team leader to predict product price and analyze profitability using regression models including multivariate regression, Random Forest, Gradient Boost, XGBoost with Scikit-Learn, achieved ~20% revenue increase
- Created a classification model to accurately predict COVID-19 patients' status, and performed SMOTE to solve the binary classification imbalance problem; based on the AUC values, adopted the XGBoost model to predict patients' status

### Research Scientist/Data Scientist

Raleigh, NC

Pidilite USA Innovation Center

07/2017-10/2018

 Optimized formulation methods to solve the adhesive bubble issues using gradient descent search skills, performed data processing, visualized experiment conditions and results; achieved the desired product properties within three months

## Research Scientist/Data Scientist

East Lansing, MI

Michigan State University

05/2016-06/2017

• Built a forecasting model to predict the concentrations of aromatic compounds in different flavor beverages using polynomial regression algorithm; conducted univariate and bivariate analysis to explore data trend and select features; and regularization technique to avoid overfitting; adopted polynomial regression model with degree 3, and achieved high metric R<sup>2</sup> value (0.98); the prediction model replaced the CocaCola company's previous laborious lab method and saved money for chemical materials

### Research Scientist/Data Scientist

Baton Rouge, LA

Louisiana State University Agricultural Center

08/2008-12/2010

• Used statistical analysis methods to link the underground carbon transformation to the aboveground emissions of carbon and non-carbon greenhouse gases

#### Research Scientist

Xinxiang, Henan, China

Henan Normal University

07/2006-07/2008

• Predicted hybrid materials properties using simulation methods; the optimized stable microstructures information is close to the experimental results of hydrotalcites

### **EDUCATION**

| Ph.D. | Polymer Chemistry  | University of Akron                       | Akron, OH       | 05/2016 |
|-------|--------------------|---|-----------------|---------|
| M.S.  | Physical Chemistry | Beijing University of Chemical Technology | Beijing, China  | 06/2006 |
| B.S.  | Chemistry          | Henan Normal University                   | Xinxiang, Henan | 06/2003 |